Contatta

+34 646457747 (Mobile) allocca.pino@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/giuseppeallocca-itechnician (LinkedIn) fab.academany.org/2018/labs/ fablabsiena/students/giuseppeallocca/ (Personal)

Competenze principali

С

Python

Microsoft Windows

Certifications

JAVA

Project Management Support Certificate

DIPLOMA FABLAB FAB ACADEMY MIT BOSTON

Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript

PHP

Giuseppe Allocca

IT TECHNICIAN, IOT MAKER, HELP-DESK, Digital graphics, WordPress, Full-Stack Developer In training

Sitges, Catalogna, Spagna

Riepilogo

Since I was a child I have always been in love with technology. Over the past 20 years, I have balanced my passion between Hardware and Software.

I am fascinated by the Internet of Things, prototyping, Cloud technology, Front, and Back-end development.

I have a natural predisposition to problem solving, analytical mind, and I am always curious to learn new things.

Over the years I have gained excellent experience in managing users and technical issues.

My skills in applied electronics and new technologies allow me to manage technical support completely and efficiently.

I strongly believe that the passion for what we do determines the result of our work.

I love my job, providing technical support to users and solving their technical issues makes me satisfied.

The smile of the people I have helped motivates me to move forward in my work and always try to improve myself, as a person and as a professional.

I am currently a student at OpenBootCamp (starting October 2021) in order to obtain certifications as a Full Stack Programmer.<HTML +CSS+JAVASCRIPT+JAVA+PYTHON>

Esperienza

Webhelp

Customer Representative Bose Italia giugno 2022 - Present (7 mesi)

Barcellona, Catalogna, Spagna

Second level technical support for BOSE ITALIA customers - Products connected to the network

SAP management, phone and mail support. Technical troubleshooting

OpenBootcamp

Student in OpenBootCamp Full Stack Developer (training) ottobre 2021 - Present (1 anno 3 mesi)

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

Front end: html +css+js

Back-end: Java+Python+Nodejs+C#

Open Inmo Barcelona

Real Estate and RRSS service technician and graphic design aprile 2021 - luglio 2021 (4 mesi)

Sant Pere de Ribes, Catalonia, Spain

Technical management, 2D and 3D graphic editing, Wordpress editing, Photoshop, Lightroom, RRSS Management, Activity Supervision

Teleperformance

IT Technical Leader

febbraio 2020 - novembre 2020 (10 mesi)

Barcelona Area, Spain

Management of the IT and logistics department.

Hardware and Software Support for Business Users.

User management in Active Directory, Azure, Citrix Cloud, VPN.

Google Assets Management and support for Google Agents as an external collaborator.

Freelance, self-employed

IT Consultant

maggio 2019 - febbraio 2020 (10 mesi)

Barcellona, Spagna

IT consultant for companies and individuals, disk image backup system with Acronis True Image Technology

Prima Foundation

Website Administrator - Help Desk - Hardware /Software and Graphics Support

agosto 2018 - aprile 2019 (9 mesi)

Barcelona

Management of the IT and logistics department, purchases, relations with external suppliers.

Hardware and Software Support for Business Users.

Technical training for employees.

User management via Google G-suite.

Configuration, maintenance, updating, diagnostics, and repair of company IT equipment.

Management of the company website, programming of implementations in PHP, and HTML in WordPress CMS.

Database management and maintenance, processing of statistical data, and related graphs in Excel (pivot tables).

Realization of Infographics and Layout of Slides in Microsoft Powerpoint.

GSK

IT Consultant , Help Desk - Hardware /Software and Logistic Support ottobre 2016 - luglio 2017 (10 mesi)

Siena, Tuscany, Italy

I worked as an IT consultant, managing 3000 assets to be migrated between two pharmaceutical companies.(Novartis and GSK) have provided technical support to users, for backup, training, hardware and software configuration, Logistic operations planning and Communication management.

Euronics Italia S.p.A.

IT Technician, Management of the technical assistance center novembre 2010 - maggio 2013 (2 anni 7 mesi)

Siena, Tuscany, Italy

- Help-Desk ,Hardware and Software Support/Procurement and Repair
- Database management, Graphic Support, Sale of electronic products
- Network services management and Complete support for clients

Trony

IT Technician, Management of the technical assistance center settembre 2003 - novembre 2010 (7 anni 3 mesi)

Siena, Tuscany, Italy

- Help-Desk: Hardware and Software Support/Procurement and Repair
- Database management, Graphic Support, Sale of electronic products
- Network services management, Printers and peripherals, support for clients

Computer Discount Inc

IT Technician, Management of the technical assistance center dicembre 2000 - settembre 2003 (2 anni 10 mesi)

Siena, Tuscany, Italy

- Help-Desk: Hardware and Software Support/Procurement and Repair
- Database management, Graphic Support, Sale of electronic products
- Network services management, Printers and peripherals, support for clients

Formazione

OpenBootcamp

FullStack Developer, Computer Programming, Specific Applications · (ottobre 2021)

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Fab Academy 2018 at Santa Chiara Lab - Siena University (Italy), Information Technology / IOT / New Technologies · (2018 - 2019)

Università degli Studi di Siena